<refsect2 id='opt_instance'>
<title>
  Instance declaration for multi decoding
</title>

<para>
The following arguments will create a new configuration set with
default parameters, and switch current set to it.  Jconf parameters
specified after the option will be set into the current set.
</para>
<para>
To do multi-model decoding, these argument should be specified at
the first of each model / search instances with different names.
Any options before the first instance definition will be IGNORED.
</para>
<para>
When no instance definition is found (as older version of Julius), all
the options are assigned to a default instance named
<literal>_default</literal>.
</para>
<para>
Please note that decoding with a single LM and multiple AMs is not
fully supported.  For example, you may want to construct the
jconf file as following.
<informalexample>
<programlisting>
 -AM am_1 -AM am_2
 -LM lm (LM spec..)
 -SR search1 am_1 lm
 -SR search2 am_2 lm
</programlisting>
</informalexample>
This type of model sharing is not supported yet, since some part
of LM processing depends on the assigned AM.  Instead, you can
get the same result by defining the same LMs for each AM, like this:
<informalexample>
<programlisting>
 -AM am_1 -AM am_2
 -LM lm_1 (LM spec..)
 -LM lm_2 (same LM spec..)
 -SR search1 am_1 lm_1
 -SR search2 am_2 lm_2
</programlisting>
</informalexample>
</para>

<variablelist>

  <varlistentry>
    <term>
      <option>
	-AM
      </option>
      <replaceable>name</replaceable>
    </term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	Create a new AM configuration set, and switch current to the
	new one.  You should give a unique name.  (Rev.4.0)
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>
      <option>
	-LM
      </option>
      <replaceable>name</replaceable>
    </term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	Create a new LM configuration set, and switch current to the
	new one.  You should give a unique name.  (Rev.4.0)
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>
      <option>
	-SR
      </option>
      <replaceable>name</replaceable>
      <replaceable>am_name</replaceable>
      <replaceable>lm_name</replaceable>
    </term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	Create a new search configuration set, and switch current to
	the new one.  The specified AM and LM will be assigned to it.
	The <replaceable>am_name</replaceable> and
	<replaceable>lm_name</replaceable> can be either name or ID
	number.  You should give a unique name.  (Rev.4.0)
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>
  <varlistentry>
    <term>
      <option>
	-AM_GMM
      </option>
    </term>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	A special command to switch AM configuration to that of GMM.
	The current AM will be switched to the GMM one, so be careful
	not to confuse with normal AM configurations.  (Rev.4.0)
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </varlistentry>

</variablelist>
</refsect2>
